<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
 *
 * This help file was generated from freqz.sci using help_from_sci().
 *
 -->

<refentry version="5.0-subset Scilab" xml:id="freqz" xml:lang="en"
          xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
          xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
          xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
          xmlns:ns3="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
          xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
          xmlns:scilab="http://www.scilab.org"
          xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">

  <refnamediv>
    <refname>freqz</refname>
    <refpurpose>This function returns the complex frequency response H of the rational IIR filter whose numerator and denominator coefficients are B and A, respectively.</refpurpose>
  </refnamediv>


<refsynopsisdiv>
   <title>Calling Sequence</title>
   <synopsis>
   [H, W] = freqz(B, A, N, "whole")
   [H, W] = freqz(B)
   [H, W] = freqz(B, A)
   [H, W] = freqz(B, A, N)
   H = freqz(B, A, W)
   [H, W] = freqz(..., FS)
   freqz(...)
   </synopsis>
</refsynopsisdiv>

<refsection>
   <title>Parameters</title>
   <variablelist>
   <varlistentry><term>B, A, N:</term>
      <listitem><para> Integer or Vector</para></listitem></varlistentry>
   </variablelist>
</refsection>

<refsection>
   <title>Description</title>
   <para>
Return the complex frequency response H of the rational IIR filter whose numerator and denominator coefficients are B and A, respectively.
   </para>
   <para>
The response is evaluated at N angular frequencies between 0 and 2*pi.
   </para>
   <para>
The output value W is a vector of the frequencies.
   </para>
   <para>
If A is omitted, the denominator is assumed to be 1 (this corresponds to a simple FIR filter).
   </para>
   <para>
If N is omitted, a value of 512 is assumed. For fastest computation, N should factor into a small number of small primes.
   </para>
   <para>
If the fourth argument, "whole", is omitted the response is evaluated at frequencies between 0 and pi.
   </para>
   <para>
'freqz (B, A, W)'
   </para>
   <para>
Evaluate the response at the specific frequencies in the vector W. The values for W are measured in radians.
   </para>
   <para>
'[...] = freqz (..., FS)'
   </para>
   <para>
Return frequencies in Hz instead of radians assuming a sampling rate FS. If you are evaluating the response at specific frequencies W, those frequencies should be requested in Hz rather than radians.
   </para>
   <para>
'freqz (...)'
   </para>
   <para>
Plot the magnitude and phase response of H rather than returning them.
</para>
</refsection>

<refsection>
   <title>Examples</title>
   <programlisting role="example"><![CDATA[
H = freqz([1,2,3], [4,3], [1,2,5])
ans =
0.4164716 - 0.5976772i  - 0.4107690 - 0.2430335i    0.1761948 + 0.6273032i
   ]]></programlisting>
</refsection>
</refentry>
