<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--
 *
 * This help file was generated from ifwht.sci using help_from_sci().
 *
 -->

<refentry version="5.0-subset Scilab" xml:id="ifwht" xml:lang="en"
          xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
          xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
          xmlns:svg="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg"
          xmlns:ns3="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
          xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"
          xmlns:scilab="http://www.scilab.org"
          xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">

  <refnamediv>
    <refname>ifwht</refname>
    <refpurpose>Compute the inverse Walsh-Hadamard transform of x using the Fast Walsh-Hadamard Transform (FWHT) algorithm</refpurpose>
  </refnamediv>


<refsynopsisdiv>
   <title>Calling Sequence</title>
   <synopsis>
   ifwht (x)
   ifwht (x, n)
   ifwht (x, n, order)
   </synopsis>
</refsynopsisdiv>

<refsection>
   <title>Parameters</title>
   <variablelist>
   <varlistentry><term>x:</term>
      <listitem><para> real or complex valued scalar or vector</para></listitem></varlistentry>
   <varlistentry><term>n:</term>
      <listitem><para> Input is truncated or extended to have a length of n</para></listitem></varlistentry>
   <varlistentry><term>order:</term>
      <listitem><para> Specifies the order in which the returned inverse Walsh-Hadamard transform</para></listitem></varlistentry>
   </variablelist>
</refsection>

<refsection>
   <title>Description</title>
   <para>
Compute the inverse Walsh-Hadamard transform of x using the Fast Walsh-Hadamard Transform (FWHT) algorithm. If the input is a matrix, the inverse FWHT is calculated along the columns of x.
The number of elements of x must be a power of 2; if not, the input will be extended and filled with zeros. If a second argument is given, the input is truncated or extended to have length n.
The third argument specifies the order in which the returned inverse Walsh-Hadamard transform coefficients should be arranged. The order may be any of the following strings:
   </para>
   <para>
"sequency"
The coefficients are returned in sequency order. This is the default if order is not given.
   </para>
   <para>
"hadamard"
The coefficients are returned in Hadamard order.
   </para>
   <para>
"dyadic"
The coefficients are returned in Gray code order.
</para>
</refsection>
</refentry>
